Interaction Design & Communications

Diligent User Experience Designer who undertakes complex assignments, meets tight deadlines, and delivers superior performance. Possesses practical knowledge in building multi-faceted designs geared towards increasing user engagement and goal resolution. Applies strong digital analytical skills to inform senior management of trends in engagement and completion. Operates with a strong sense of urgency and thrives in a fast pace setting.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Mutual of Omaha • March 2016 - Present

Mutual of Omaha is a full-service, multi-line provider of insurance and financial service products for individuals, businesses and groups throughout the United States

Senior User Interaction Designer

- Design, facilitate, and analyze various user research activities, including user testing, interviews, and observations
- Leverage user research insights and business strategy requirements to create innovate interactive web/mobile application concepts, and drive them to completion for Mutual of Omaha and Mutual of Omaha Bank
- Collaborate with design team members on all aspects of user-centered design including information architecture, task analysis, user flows and stories, navigation, content hierarchies, interaction design, and functioning prototypes based on design principles and best practices
- Advocate user focus across the organization and communicate the value and principles of user-centered design.
- Use Goal Directed Design to iterate on ideas based upon validated learning, critique, and collaboration.

West Interactive Services • September 2014 - March 2016

West Interactive is a global leader for delivering enterprise contact center transformation. West Interactive is a subsidiary of West Corporation, which offers a broad range of communications and network infrastructure solutions designed to help organizations manage or support critical communications.

Senior User Interaction Designer

- Lead design initiatives for new clients, provide performance analysis for developed applications, and mentor fellow designers.
- Collaborate with product managers, software engineers, and end users to design and develop interface mockups and prototypes for new features and enhancements; solicit and incorporate feedback; create low and high-fidelity prototypes of proposed designs for Comcast, RCN, and SuddenLink Cable Communications.
- Create business requirements documents that clearly and concisely describe the ideal interactive voice response system for the Cable Communications client, and that facilitate the design and development of a UI that addresses the target persona and incorporates key usability concepts.
- Serve as a liaison between developers and internal/external clients to ensure that user interface and design requirements are implemented appropriately and reflect end user needs.
- Design user interface elements for all levels of the interface including interface posture, navigation frameworks, pages, components, dialogs, graphical elements that are highly optimized around user goals and needs.

Nexadental • March 2014 - December 2014

NEXADENTAL has become a leading supplier of dental materials to the oral healthcare industry serving the pedo, perio, surgical, endo, and general dental specialties. Nexadental uses internal expertise and outside University or doctor assisted training programs to better prepare our staff to assist with product selections.

Visual Communications Designer

- Redesigned the Cfast websites to increase user engagement, and capture visitor's information in order to effectively market the product to Dental professionals and consumers.
- Reorganized the email marketing program and doubled the open and click rates for marketing emails within two weeks of implementation.
- Collaborate with the Director of Marketing to execute an effective web content strategy.

• Work with the executive team to roll out new products, and effectively market them to our customer base.

RURAL MEDIA GROUP, RFD-TV • May 2012-March 2014

Rural Media Group, Inc. is the world's leading provider of multimedia content dedicated to the rural and western lifestyle. RFD-TV is the nation's first 24-hour television network dedicated to serving the needs and interests of rural America with programming focused on agriculture, equine and the rural lifestyle, along with traditional country music and entertainment.

Experience Designer

- Successfully led and executed the re-design of Rural Media Group's flagship website, moving the site to the WorldNow Content Management System
- Provide high visibility for programs and events through the use of compelling web content, including print, video, photography, audio and graphics.
- Manage a team that performed daily site updates all RMG properties
- Deliver web and advertising statistics to marketing, sales, and the executive team

INDEPENDENT MARKETING CONSULTANT • 2010-Present

Independent consulting provides the opportunity to try out new ideas that may not work well in the mainstream work environment. The ideas that are received well in the independent marketing situations are translated into mainstream media and design.

Digital Strategist

- Write copy for a multitude of outlets including web, print, and advertising
- Design digital and print newsletters, flyers, advertisements, to improve the visibility of businesses
- Shoot and edit video, compose small animations, in Final Cut, Premiere Pro, and After Effects
- Create advertising campaigns to get clients in touch with potential and existing customers

EDUCATION:

Bachelors of Science in Communications
MAJOR: Communications
MINOR: Marketing & Design

UNIVERSITY OF NEBRASKA • OMAHA, NE, 2011

Bachelors of Science in Journalism

Major: Photojournalism

CREIGHTON UNIVERSITY • OMAHA, NE, 2009

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Agile/Lean Development • SDLC • Microsoft Visio • Adobe Creative Suite • Google Apps • WorldNow CMS • Wordpress CMS • HTML • CSS • Javascript • Windows • Mac • Chrome OS • Sharepoint • Invision • Sketch • Usability Testing • Axure